ADESUWA NKEM OMOZUSI

Plot 3, Good Homes Estate, Ajah, Lagos, Nigeria.

Email: omozusiadesuwa@gmail.com

Phone: +2348025101545

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/adesuwaomozusiugboaja

Professional Summary

A Legal Professional with almost a decade experience and strong legal background in family law, property law, energy law and human rights.

An enthusiastic and avid researcher currently seeking a PhD position to explore and contribute to the field of international human rights.

Education

Post Graduate Degree

• Institution: University of Ibadan

• Location: Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria

• **Degree:** LLM Masters of Law

• **Graduation Date:** August, 2016

• **Grade/CGPA:** Second Class Upper Degree, 5.3/7.0

• Thesis/Dissertation Title: International Legal Framework and institution on Renewable Energy: its application to Nigeria.

• **Advisor:** Dr J.O Akintayo

Undergraduate Degree

• Institution: Igbinedion University

• Location: Okada, Edo State, Nigeria

• **Degree:** B.L (Bachelor of Law)

• Graduation Date: November, 2012

• Grade/CGPA: Second Class Upper Degree, 4.42 / 5.0

Research Experience

[Household Energy Consumption]
Institution: University of Ibadan
Location: Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria

Dates: April, 2016 – May, 2016

Description:

- The project was to collate data on household energy consumption in Ojor Community, Ibadan, Nigeria.
- The methodology was personal interview and survey with residents in the community.
- I engaged individuals in a community in Ibadan, Nigeria on the reason for their most preferred source of energy, reason for their decision, and their knowledge on energy conservation.

 Data collated was interpreted into household energy consumption of the community for National Databank for the Energy Commission of Nigeria.

Work Experience

Team Lead, Family Law Practice

• Company: ForestHill Legal Practice

• Location: Lagos, Nigeria

• Dates: January 2022 – Till date

Responsibilities:

- Handling divorce proceedings, child custody and property division cases. Representing clients in family law related suits.
- Representing clients in cases involving child welfare, child abuse, neglect or adoption.
- Preparing wills, trusts, and representing clients for probate matters.
- Providing guidance on family law matters, such as prenuptial agreements, postnuptial agreement, and sale for family property.
- Drafting and documentation preparation on family and property law.
- Representing clients in mediation, arbitration on family and property law matters.

Legal Officer

Company: GPO PROPERTIES LIMITED

Location: Lagos, Nigeria

Dates: October, 2016 – December, 2021

Responsibilities:

- Reviewed and drafted property related contracts for Landlords and Tenants, such as lease agreement, service contracts, facility management contracts, property sale contracts, tenancy agreements, and quit notices.
- Ensured company's compliance with relevant laws, regulations, and industry standards.
- Liaised with external counsel on litigation matters in property related matters, including property damage claims and breach of contract.
- Verified property ownership and title at the Lands registry.
- Conducted due diligence process and procedures for property acquisition or lease.
- Advisory on legal aspects of property development projects.
- Identified and mitigated potential legal risks for property owners.

Publications

- The need for the introduction of Competition Law in Nigerian Universities by Uwadi Eyinnaya and Adesuwa Omozusi
 http://www.academia.edu/13928382/The_Need_for_the_Introductionof_Competition_Law_in_Nigeria.
- Acts that are considered domestic violence in Lagos State- The Nigerian Blawg http://www.legalnaija.com/2017/09/acts-considered-domestic-violence-in.html.

Conferences and Presentations

- The nexus between climate justice and section 15, "the right of a child to free, compulsory and universal basic education" of the Child Right Act in Nigeria, accepted for an online presentation at the Conference on "Child/Youth-Friendly Climate Justice: Progress and Opportunities" at the University College Cork, Ireland on 30th September-1st October, 2024.
- Torture Camps: "A comparative analysis of legislation on Rehabilitation Centers in Nigeria and other Common Law Jurisdictions in Africa" in the panel on "Plenary 4. International Family Law"- a paper presented as Keynote Speaker at the International Society of Family Law, 18th (Golden Jubilee) World Conference. 15th July, 2023 at the University of Antwerp, Belgium.
- Widowhood and Informal Mutual Support Network: A panel study on welfare outcomes in Nigeria, by Efobi Uchenna, Ajefu Joseph and Omozusi Adesuwa- A paper presented at the 28th IAFFE Annual Conference at Glasgow Caledonian University, June 27- 29, 2019.
- Fertility Law Presentations on Designer Babies: "Now your baby can be custom made." A presentation at Aluko and Oyebode Legal Practice Seminar, November, 2018.

Awards and Honors

• **Best Graduating Student (Class of 2012)** Igbinedion University, Okada, Edo State, Nigeria, 2012.

Professional Affiliations

- Nigerian Bar Association, Member, 2013 Present.
- International Federation of Women Lawyers (FIDA NIGERIA), Member, 2022 Present.
- Association for Fertility and Reproductive Health, Member, 2020-Present.

Skills

• Languages: [English], [Advanced Level] Native Speaker